大伙儿会怀念Joe的
Joe will be missed.
深切缅怀 大家热爱Joe
Very much missed. We liked Joe.
谁会不喜欢他呢
A hard man not to like.
明天的事谁都说不准
Tomorrow ain't promised to no one.
不过 该继续的继续
Meanwhile, we go on.
生意也好 生活也罢
In business, in life,
做生意最重要就是要有靠得住的人
what you learn to appreciate the most is a dependable man.
过去如此 往后也一样
One day, same as the next.
嗯 跟着Joe我学了不少
Yeah, I learned a lot from watching Joe.
我们只跟你或者你副手联络
We deal with you or your second.
别人一个不行 不能让人知道我们
No one else. No one else knows our names.
不能让别人联系我们
No one else contacts us.
明白?
Understand?
要联系我们 只能用这个
To contact us, use this... only.
我不用手机的
Man, I don't talk on no cellphones.
给 用它约个午饭没什么
Here. To call for lunch, you can talk.
用它打给女朋友也没事
To call your girl, you can talk.
甚至打给你律师也没事
To call your lawyer even, you can talk -
你跟律师之间的谈话有保密协议
the law says that is between you and the lawyer.
明白吗?
All right?
问问电影院在放啥电影都没关系
To find out what movie is playing down the street, you can talk.
这都没问题 说这些是为了让他们知道
All of that is good because all of that tells them
没啥好偷听的
there is nothing good to hear.
但是 生意上的事
But, for business,
不能在电话上说
we do not talk on the phone.
- 决不能 - 行
- Never. - Right.
这个Joe教过我
I mean, Joe taught me that.
但这个怎么说
But what about... What is...
- 事儿办得怎样? - 节哀顺变呗
- How'd that play? - Man overcame his grief.
你现在有没有君临天下的感觉?
Do it feel like a crown on your head right now?
有没有?
Do it?
老子现在就这感觉
'Cause that's what I'm wearin' on my head.
该庆祝下
We should celebrate.
啥?
Yeah?
去大西洋城
Atlantic City.
还不是庆祝的时候
Can't play like that now.
Omar可能会采取行动 你知道的
Omar gonna make a move. You know this.
我要往家去一趟
Yo, I need to go past home.
- 带我一程? - 你知道我多喜欢你家人
- You mind a ride? - You know I like your peoples.
我要告诉他们有阵子不能回去了
I gotta tell 'em I'm not gonna be comin' round for a time.
你的角色演完了
You stepped up and made your play.
该轮到我上场了
Now I gotta make mine.
* When you walk through the garden *
火线重案组 第五季 第5集
the wire S05E05
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
www.1000fr.net presents
"住大街上又不代表他们没有想法" - Haynes
- 至少四起 - 明白了
- At least four. - Got it.
我们在查旧卷宗 看看有没有更多
We're going back through old cases, so we could find more than that.
- 还有什么? - 作案动机可能和性有关
- What else? - And the motive now seems sexual.
什么叫和性有关?
What do you mean sexual?
有人鸡奸流浪汉?
Is someone sodomizing homeless men?
具体的我不能说
I can't get that specific.
不具体我怎么写?
How can I not get specific?
就说凶手是出于性冲动而发动袭击的
Just say the killer is acting from sexual compulsions.
详细情况属于案件机密
Anything more detailed we need to keep in the case file.
我不知道 长官..
I don't know, detective..
上次就没法发上都市版
Last time, I couldn't get it out front
我问下主编再打给你吧
Let me run it by my desk and call you back. All right?
好吧
All right.
差佬那儿怎么说?
Anything late from cop shop?
最近几起凶杀案的后续情况
Follow-ups on the recent murders.
抓获一名嫌犯 Hampden的家庭谋杀
An arrest on one, which was the domestic cutting from Hampden.
东巴尔的摩的几起涉毒案中没有人员逮捕
No arrests in a couple of drug-relateds from East Baltimore.
给我点背景资料
OK, give me a bit for the budget line.
家庭谋杀受害者Patricia Boggus 发现死于车中
Domestic was a Patricia Boggus, found in her car.
涉毒凶杀中的Joseph Stewart 发现死在客厅内
Drug-relateds were one Joseph Stewart, found in his dining room,
还有名Nathaniel Manns  在后巷车库发现
and one Nathaniel Manns, found in an alley garage.
每件都弄几张照片
A couple graphs on each.
写得简短一些
Write it as a single short.
还有一起流浪汉谋杀案的消息
Also, I got word on another homeless murder.
办案的警官说互相有联系
The detective on it says it's related.
他说是性犯罪
He says it's sexual.
- 性犯罪? 被强奸了? - 他不肯确认
- Sexual? They being raped? - He wouldn't confirm that.
他就说这些谋杀在性质上与性有关
He just says that the killings are sexual in nature.
有什么写什么
Write what you got.
我四点编辑会的时候提一下 看要不要写
I'll run it by the 4:00, see if it takes.
这次起诉背后是长达18个月的调查取证
This indictment is the result of an 18-month investigation
由州检察官和巴尔的摩警局共同参与
by the State's Attorney's office and the Baltimore Police Department.
它为任何代议制政府的基本问题
And it shines a light on a cornerstone issue
人民对公仆的信任问题点亮了明灯
for any representative government - public trust of public servants.
参议员Davis污蔑了这种信任
Senator Davis abused that trust.
他拿权力和影响力做交易
He traded on his power and influence
把本地的企业和竞选捐助人
so that he could use local businesses and campaign donors
当做他的私人提款机
as his personal A.T. M. Machine.
他创办了一系列慈善和非营利性机构
He created a network of charitable and non-profit organizations
只为了牟取钱财中饱私囊 这背叛了...
whose purpose was to accumulate cash for his private use, betraying...
Rhonda Pearlman?
我是Bill Zorzi 太阳报联邦法制版的
Bill Zorzi, covering federal court for The Sun.
哦 你好
Right. How do you do?
不是趁着你这儿大日子骚扰您
Not to be all petulant on your special day here,
可啥时候起本城的检察官
but since when does a prosecutor in this town
拉人游街示众都不给日报打电话了?
stage a perp walk and not call the daily newspaper?
我们给Gail Gibson打电话 在他语音信箱留言了啊
We called Gail Gibson. Left a message on her voice mail.
Gail四个月前就离职做自由撰稿人去了
Gail left for a freelance gig four months ago.
他的语音信箱还在啊
Well, her voice mail still works.
谁接替他跑法制版了呢?
Who's replacing her on city courts?
从今往后 可别再把我关在外面了
From now on, just don't jam me up like that again.
...他将为自己的欺诈行为付出代价
...he must be held accountable for his fraudulent actions.
参议员Davis将我们的立法机构
Senator Davis has opened our legislative body
卷入钱权交易
to monetary persuasions.
这是明知故犯
He has done this knowingly
完全无视他所代表的办公室
and with complete disregard for the office that he represents.
- 正是这种不当行为... - 感觉怎么样 Clay?
- It is this kind of impropriety... - How's it feel, Clay?
吃不了兜着走了吧?
No fun on the ass end, is it?
你说的 Norman
You said it, Norman.
君子报仇十年不晚
There's the short con and the long con.
你得发表个声明
You're gonna need a statement.
别太幸灾乐祸
Nothing too joyful.
没确保这厮彻底死了之前 先别在他坟头跳舞
Don't dance on Clay's grave until you're sure the motherfucker's dead.
Clay没可能逃过这一劫
Clay ain't getting up from this.
就是为了不得罪他的选众 你也不能显得太高兴了
Also, you don't want to piss off his base, being too gleeful about it.
他还有选众?
That guy still has a base?
整这么出还有人敢保他?
After all the shit he's pulled?
我跟你说 这家伙看着倒挺有市长范儿的
I'll tell you one thing - that fella is looking pretty damn mayoral.
肯定比Nerese强
More than Nerese, definitely.
这件事为他的形象加分不少 看来Bond先生已经遥遥领先了
With the profile he gets from this, I'd say it's Mr. Bond's race to lose.
...由普通法院审理
...and remain under common court.
参议员Davis将为这笔资金负责
Senator Davis will have to account for that money.
- 跟你闺女说什么了? - 说我要去出差
- What'd you tell your girl? - I'm away on business.
得几星期不能回家
I won't be around for a couple weeks.
- 应该不用那么久 - 希望不会
- Shouldn't be more than that. - Better not.
Trainor老师说今年到明年 每天都要学一道题
Miss Trainor say we gonna learn a problem like that every day for this year and the next.
要背出来?
You mean memorize 'em?
嗯 背得滚瓜烂熟
Yeah. Learn it by heart.
题目和答案都要背出来
Learn the question. Learn the answer, too.
因为明年的马里兰州统考要考?
'Cause them questions gonna be on the M.S.A. Test next year.She tell you all that?
Trainor老师说要是选择之前成绩不提高
Miss Trainor say if the scores don't go up before the selection
所有老师都会被炒鱿鱼
all the teachers gonna get fired.
选择? 什么意思?
Selection? What she mean?
就是投票啊什么的
When the people vote for whoever.
你是说选举吧?
You mean an election?
大伙都说你是玻璃
Nigga think you all that.
你这是要干嘛?
Now, why you gonna go and do that?
- Dukie都快哭了 看呐 - 你他妈有病啊
- Dukie about to cry. - Fuck is wrong with you?
我有病 我在这儿拼命干活
Nothin' wrong with me! I'm gettin' stuff done.
你他妈躲屋里扮小娘儿们
You up in some house playin' like a lil' bitch.
- 踢死丫个死基佬 - 弄死他!
- Smack his faggoty little ass. - Get that little jog-ass!
最后是关于Bud Selig的长篇系列报道 (美国职棒大联盟主席)
...Finally, we've got that 40-inch thumbsucker on Bud Selig
棒球界对于最近兴奋剂事件的不同反应
and baseball's half-hearted response to the latest recommendations on steroid use.
基本上俱乐部老板对Bud很满意 球员工会则装聋作哑
Bottom line is the owners think Bud is swell, the players' union is staying mum,
Bonds保持着本垒打记录 大家都假装这事会不了了之
Bonds has a home-run record and everyone's pretending the issue will go away.
- 这也算是新闻么? - 头版准备放什么?
- And there's news in there? - What do you like for the front?
显然是Clay Davis的起诉
The Clay Davis indictment, obviously.
伊拉克问题的国会听证
Congressional hearings on Iraq.
Price写的Carcetti为竞选州长 筹集资金的这篇也不错
Price's piece on how much Carcetti raised for his gubernatorial run is solid.
专题写John Waters在巴市拍电影 如果图片效果好的话
The feature on John Waters filming in Baltimore could go out front if the art is good.
有他和几名儿童演员的合照
We have him posing with a couple of child actors.
这不犯法么? (该导演为公开的同性恋)
Is that allowed?
好了好了 不要混淆个人癖好和艺术嘛
Now, now, let's not confuse the auteur with his art.
- 还有别的吗? - 刚得到的消息
- Anything else? - This came in late,
关于又一起流浪汉被谋杀的案件
this business about another homeless man being murdered -
- 可能有新的进展 - 还有其他流浪汉被谋杀?
- that might have some play. - Other homeless men were murdered?
我们一周前报道过三起类似案件之间 可能存在的联系 本地新闻
We ran a short piece a week ago about possible connections in three cases.Inside metro.
据说动机与性有关
The motive's said to be sexual,
但警方对具体情况闪烁其词
but the cops are being cryptic about what exactly that means.
好吧 在次版登一下
Well, we could run it inside,
多报道一点 看事态如何发展
but report it some more, see where it goes.
现在上头版还太含糊
Right now, it's a little vague for A-1.
好吧 过几个小时再看有什么进展
OK, then, we'll see where we are in a couple hours.
听我说 Duke
I told you, Duke.
只要你一句话 我就去废了他们
I fuck 'em up good. Just say the word, man.
不 不能老让你替我出头
Nah, man, I can't have you steppin' up for me any more.
那好吧 跟他说说
Yeah, well. Talk to the man.
他能帮你
He'll set you straight.
嘿 Dennis先生
Yo, Mr. Dennis.
能让我参加训练么
I need to train with you some.
看看
See that.
怎么搞的?
What happened?
没什么 就是受够了 真的
It ain't no thing. I'm gettin' a little tired of it, that's all.
好吧 孩子
A'ight, son.
找副手套带上 看看你的身手
Get some gloves on and let's see where you at.
这些都一清二楚
It's all pretty straightforward.
我很奇怪为何你们的律师要一拖再拖
I'm surprised your lawyers went to the trouble of getting it postponed.
大概因为我们是按小时付费吧
Maybe 'cause we was payin' by the hour.
不管怎么说 你们都事儿犯得不小啊
In any event, you got a lot going for you here.
前面车登记着 后面暗槽里藏着枪
Car registered to a front, guns in a secreted compartment.
登记车的那女人 她不能再坐牢了
The woman we registered it to, she can't do no time.
我们只是借她名字而已
Just a name we used.
那找个能背黑锅的
Then get someone who can.
找个无牵无挂的
Preferably someone without priors,
信得过 顶得了风险的
someone you trust to stand the charge.
还有这事儿替我办下
Also came past with this here.
把这笔钱给洗了
More money made clean.
等你想出怎么办了 通知我一声
When you figure out what to do with that, holler at me.
怎么联系你?
How do I do that?
410-915-0909
410-915-0909.
还有其他的吗?
Anything else?
没了 掐表吧
Nah, take me off your clock.
烦人事儿真不少
Fuckin' mope pisses me off.
放开说吧
Be generous.
我觉得本事务所托Stanfield一伙的鸿福
I have a feeling this firm is going to have quite a payday
可要大大地发达了哇
from Mr. Stanfield and his people.
他刚给了我他的电话
He just gave me his phone number.
只要他Marlo Stanfield用上手机 用不了多久
If Marlo Stanfield is using a cellphone, it's just a matter of time
就能开始进入案前行动准备了
before we're up to our asses in pre-trial motions,
可以申请监听了
litigating a wiretap case.
Joe把他交给我们得正是时候
Joe gave him to us just in time.
现在怎么办?
What now?
这个你不打算改了?
You need to attribute that?
- 啥? - 第五段 这个从句
- What? - Fifth graph, the dependent clause.
广泛的权钱交易模式形成于某某年之中
The one about a pattern of widespread  influence-peddling"over a period of years."
起诉里要么写了要么没写
Either the indictment shows it or it doesn't.
还有 你连着三段都用动名词开头 看
Besides which, you begin three graphs in a row with a gerund. Look.
你指指戳戳的我怎么写啊?
How do you expect me to write with your fucking fingers in my eyes?
好歹让我交了初稿你再批判嘛
At least let me turn my copy in before you stomp on it.
好家伙 Zorz
Attaboy, Zorz.
他们要我多报道一点 我还真不知道怎么写
They want more reporting on this, but I don't see where it can go from here.
警察宣称有性动机
The cops are selling a sexual motive
又不愿意多说
but they won't explain it any more than that.
你从哪儿得到的消息
Who are you dealing with?
办案的警官啊
Detective who has the case.
他想让这事见报?
And he wants publicity?
没想到你会回来
Didn't know if you'd come back.
当初拿了不少钱啊
Took a lot of money with you.
跟钱没关系 伙计
It wasn't about the money, bro.
一点儿关系都没有
Wasn't never about that.
是他吗
Is that him?
老Monk喜欢住公寓嘛 我懂了
Old Monk prefer the condo life, I see.
瞧不上排屋是吧
Too good for a row house.
还带着保镖
Movin' with muscle, too.
看来他们算到你会采取行动
Most likely they expectin' you to make a move.
我这不来了么
An' here I am.
怎么着吧?
How 'bout that?
谢谢你同意再次和我见面
Thanks for meeting me again.
这是Scott Templeton 他跟我一起负责这报道
This is Scott Templeton. He'll be working the story with me.
我可不想你们报社人人都知道我名字
I don't want everyone at your newspaper knowing my name.
你想让这些流浪汉引起媒体注意是吧?
Look, you want these homeless cases to get attention, right?
你是不是就这意思
That's what you're trying to do.
这家伙很危险 得让大家知道
Guy's a predator. People need to know.
同意 有些事情你不便透露
Agreed. And there are things you need to keep secret
以免影响你们破案 这我明白
so that you can solve the murders. I get that.
但你不给我们点猛料我们没法报道啊
We can't do much with this story unless we give it enough juice.
猛料?
Juice?
得告诉读者是怎么回事  他为什么要这么做
We need to tell people what this is about, why he's doing it.
能读起来生动形象跃然于纸上
We need to make this thing come alive on the page
不然上头又要把报道给压了
or they're gonna bury the story again.
我都告诉你们了 跟性有关
I told you, it's sexual.
冲动强迫症之类的
Compulsion. Obsession, that kinda thing.
这算什么意思呢?
But what the fuck does that mean?
他又不是屠杀家庭主妇或勒死男女同校生
It's not like he's carving up housewives or strangling coeds, here.
你这家伙他专杀无家可归的男人
Your guy's killing homeless men.
到底为什么? 他怎么想的?
Why exactly? What's in his head?
他强奸他们吗? 鸡奸?
Is he raping them? Sodomizing them?
案件中并无发现精液成分
I don't have any semen in any of the cases.??
但他总干了什么吧?
But he's doing something, right?
他在他们手臂上绑红丝带
He ties a red ribbon around their arms.
- 红丝带? - 嗯 蝴蝶结
- A red ribbon? - Yeah, a bow.
把那些家伙当礼物一样包起来
He gift-wraps the motherfuckers.
这料够猛么?
That enough juice for you?
嗯 够古怪 可谁杀人会只为了绑红丝带
Yeah, kinky but no one kills people to tie ribbons around their arms.
能否说他们被侵犯了?
Can we say they were molested?
可以这样说吗?
Is it fair to say that?
- 那我们就写受侵犯了 - 这可不是我说的
- We'll go with molested, then. - You didn't get that from me.
- 再来一杯? - 要什么
- Another round? - What else?
你想让这故事大卖 得给我们点新鲜的
You want this story to fly, give us something different.
不能说的别说 给我们点曲折的
Keep what you need, but give us something with a twist.
色情连环杀人犯还不够曲折?
A sexual serial killer isn't enough?
人情冷漠啊 我知道
It's a cold world, I know.
他一开始会咬受害者
He's started biting them.
什么?
What?
用牙咬受害者
He's biting his victims.
大腿内侧 右侧屁股 左侧乳头
Inside thigh, right ass cheek, left nipple.
是个用牙的
He's a biter.
- 操 - 嗯
- Shit. - Yeah.
这够曲折了吧?
That twisted enough for ya?
你确定不是食人狂?
Are we talkin' cannibalism here?
目前还只是啃咬
Just biting for now.
看事态如何发展了
We'll see where it goes.
所有受害者他都咬了?
And did he bite all of them?
不是全部 只是最近几名受害者
Not all. Just the latest ones.
他在慢慢成熟
He's maturing.
- 成熟? - 嗯 这是专业术语
- Maturing? - Yeah, it's a technical term.
是连环杀手越来越执迷于此的表现
It's when a serial killer's becoming more obsessive.
对尸体的处理开始发展出复杂的模式
He starts to develop an intricate pattern in what he does with the bodies.
够诡异
It's weird stuff.
- 咬人者 很好 - 千万别透露我名字
- A biter. That's great. - My name is nowhere on this.
给你付酒钱
For your tab.
我们也想坐下喝一杯 但现在回去还能赶上二轮审编
We'd stay and have one, but we can still make the second edition.
谢了
Thanks.
你以为学点格斗术
So you thinkin' if you learn to fight some,
别人就不来欺负你了
people 'round the way gonna leave you be.
事实是 就算你学会打架
Thing is, even if you learn to fight,
别人还是一样会来找你麻烦
people gonna come at you just the same.
不像电影里拍的 你打败了一个坏蛋
It ain't like the movies where you beat up one bully
其他人就躲到一边了
and the rest just back the hell up.
我问你
Let me ask,
你说他们干嘛要这样找你茬?
why you think they even bothering to come at you the way they do?
干嘛专找你?
I mean, why you?
我懂的就这一块儿
See, all I know is that right there.
干其他事我一点用都没有
I ain't never had no use for other things.
我会打架
I could fight.
曾经一度 还能跑跑街角生意
For a time there, I could run them corners.
算不上有什么大出息
Not much life outside that, really.
- 我也在街角混过一段时间 - 干得怎么样?
- I was on the corner for a while. - How that go?
就是嘛...
Yeah, well...
我想说的是
I guess what I'm tryin' to say is...
你的成就不完全取决于你在道上的表现
not everything comes down to how you carry it in the street.
要是你的目标是混街头那当然重要
I mean, it do come down to that if you gonna be in the street.
但也不是就这一条道儿
But that ain't the only way to be.
- 在这儿就这一条道 - 是
- Round here it is. - Yeah.
在这儿是这样
Round here it is.
可世界大着呢
World is bigger than that,
至少 别人是这么跟我说的
at least, that's what they tell me.
那 怎么能从这儿去到别的世界呢?
Like... how do you get from here to the rest of the world?
我也想知道啊
I wish I knew.
Michael长得很快
Michael grew up fast.
是啊
Yeah, he did.
不过像他这样的孩子
Anyway, for a kid like that,
我的训练法子也许挺管用
my onliest plan might be fine, you know?
能帮到他们这样的孩子
Might could work for a boy like that.
可有其他技能的孩子来找我
But a kid come to me with other skills,
能追寻其他命运的
other way of being,
我只能祝他好运了
all I got is hope and wishes.
有总比没强
That's something, I guess.
希望能帮上更多啊
Wish it was more, son.
真的
I do.
谢谢
Thanks.
*流浪汉谋杀案惊现性动机*
好姑娘
Attagirl.
Alma 调查归你了 总部有什么消息你来跟进
Alma, you've got the investigation. Anything from headquarters, that's you.
我以为你要让我去调查受害者 还原死者的身份什么的
I thought I'd work back on the victims. A profile of who these guys were.
想法不错 不过我已经派Fletcher去干了
That's a nice idea, but I already sent Fletcher out on that.
- 还有什么我可干的? - 你可以去采访下流浪汉
- What's left for me to do? - You can talk to the homeless.
无家可归人员对此的反应?
React quotes from the homeless?
人家住在大街 又不代表人家没想法
Just 'cause they're in the streets doesn't mean that they lack opinions.
我去哪儿找无家可归的人啊?
Where am I gonna find homeless people?
我看家里肯定是没有喽
Not at home, I imagine.
去吧 孩子们
Go, go, my children.
看完哭鼻子吧
Read it and weep.
已经看了
I already did.
警司长看了
So did the major.
副总警监看了
So did the colonel.
新上任的副局长也看了
So did our newly christened deputy ops.
- 副局这会儿在市政厅呢 - 够快哇
- Deputy's over at city hall right now. - That was quick.
几个他妈的记者信了你的胡编乱造
Just 'cause some fuckin' reporter bought your weak shit
不代表别人也相信
does not mean everyone else buys it.
跟你赌 副局这会儿在市政厅扑火呢
Five gets you ten,deputy's over there right now,talking them back down to earth.
这疯子强奸了他们吗?
Is this nut raping them?
我还未听取办案警官的详细汇报
I haven't debriefed the investigators in detail,
但报道似乎没说有插入和射精行为
but the reports don't indicate penetration or ejaculation.
目前采取了什么行动?
What can we say we're doing already?
我们已经派了最强的警力办案
We've got good people working it.
如果不用按时下班当然更好
It would be better if I could keep them on it around the clock.
你是说加班加点?
You're talking overtime.
假如您能为这次调查破个例...
If you could lift the cap for this investigation...
成 允许两名探员不限时加班
Done. Unlimited overtime for two detectives.
一切资源供取
Anything they need.
市长  这种案子需要大家积极防范避免更多谋杀
Sir, a case like this, where we're proactively trying to prevent additional murders,
两名探员加班是不够的
requires more than two detectives.
副局 教育委员会主席跟我哭穷说
Deputy, the school board chairman telling me
他们面临裁减50名中学教师的困局
is a short hair away from laying off 50 middle-school teachers
搞不好还要冒着违反联邦共同协定的风险
and shutting down special education in every elementary school
关停所有小学的特殊教育项目
in violation of a federal consent decree.
就算我兜里有钱 也不能给你啊
??? If I've got more than an extra couple of dollars,you aren't getting it.
克服克服吧 当领导有领导的压力
Embracing the hard choice. It's one of the burdens of command.
有什么进一步保护流浪人员的措施么?
Is there anything you can do to further protect the homeless?
可以让巡逻小组散发警告
We can have patrol units spread the warning,
尽可能让大家天黑以后到收容所过夜
try to convince anyone to move into the city shelters after dark.
不能让警察在流浪汉聚集地蹲守?
Can't you have police sit on locations where the homeless gather?
那还怎么接警?
And still answer the calls?
除非值班人员加倍 那还是要加班
Not without doubling up post units, which means overtime.
又是加班
Overtime, again.
警务工作的命脉啊 市长先生
Blood in our veins, Mr. Mayor.
你是一天比一天有老大样了哇
Every day you look more like a boss.
- 去死 - 放心 不是骂你的话
- Fuck you. - I didn't mean it like a bad thing.
- 还说不是 - 嗯 是骂你
- Yeah, you did. - Yeah, I did.
- 这什么? - 来自你最忠诚朋友的礼物
- What's that? - A gift from your one true partner.
- 手机号码 Marlo Stanfield - 你哪里...
- Cellphone number, Marlo Stanfield. - How the fuck...
美军对同性恋士兵的强制保密政策
"不问不说" 跟部队那些搞同性恋的一样
Don't ask, don't tell. Like those guys sucking dick in the army.
不管我干过什么混账事 记得我这个人情
Whatever else I ever did to piss you off, remember I also did this.
还有Carv? 等你给这婊子带上手铐
And, Carv? When you put the bracelets on that bitch,
告诉他 别忘了我的摄像机
remind him again of my fuckin' camera.
你去跟他们所有人说 Royce 党团
You can tell all of 'em - Royce, the caucus,
咱安插在政府各部门那些白眼狼
all them graspin' bitches who we put in every city department
你去一个个告诉他们  要倒我也不会一个人倒
you tell every last one that I do not fall alone.
- Clay - 你以为我会为整个集团
- Clay - You think I'm gonna be the scapegoat
去当替罪羊 我呸--
for the whole damn machine? Shit.
Clarence会支持你的 他说过会替你说话
Clarence is going to stand with you. He told me so. He'll be out there.
说得容易 他现在是无官一身轻啊
Easy for him. He ain't runnin' for nothin' no more.
你和你那群人怎么不替我说话
I don't see you and your kind with me on this.
你们一个个都以为 自己坐在审判席上是吧
A whole mess o' people think they belong on the fence.
- Clay 事已至此 - 你最好别这么想
- Clay, it is what it is. - Y'all better hope not.
不然倒的可不止Clay Davis一个人
Or it ain't gonna end with Clay Davis.
你想想你刚说的话吧
Just think about what you're saying here.
你要想拖大家一起下水
You can have yourself a pity party,
那跟公诉人一古脑儿说去好了
talk all kinda shit to some prosecutor.
然后你怎么样 两眼一抹黑
You know where you'll be then? Out in the damn cold.
没有关系 没有盟友
No connections, no allies,
城里连个可落脚的地方都没有
nowhere to hang your hat in this damn town.
而如果你替我们扛下来  能扛多久扛多久
Or you carry this for all of us, carry it as far as you can.
就算最坏的情况下  他们撤了你席位
And if the worst happens, if they take your seat,
退出政坛个一两年
if you go away for a year or so
去低警戒改造营待上段时间  那又怎样?
to some minimum-security summer camp, then so what?
你回到城里来还有人记得你的名字
You come home to a town that still knows your name.
你看Burrell
Look at Burrell.
他悄悄下台 现在每年挣得比当局长时
He goes quietly and now he's making 12 a year more
多好几万 工作时间还减半
than when he was commissioner, and working half the hours.
你觉得他当初非要强出头还能得到这些?
You think that happens if he does the piss-and-moan?
检察官来来去去的
Prosecutors come and prosecutors go.
不管是输是赢 你肯定一眨眼就回来了嘛
But win or lose, you're still gonna be back around before we know it.
我说的对吗 参议员Davis?
Am I right, Senator Davis?
你要我另找家外卖么?
You want me to find another carry-out?
- 近一点的? - 你不喜欢这吃的?
- Someplace closer? - You don't like this food?
我不喜欢那些中国佬的样子
I don't like the way them Chinky motherfuckers be acting sometimes.
他们看我的眼神
The way they be lookin' at me.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
Chris来了吗?
Chris with you?
在后面呢
Behind me.
- 你穿的什么呐? - 啥?
- What you got on? - What?
你想让那死基佬知道我们打他埋伏吗?
You want that faggot to know we waitin' on his ass?
小心点就没事嘛
Just bein' careful is all.
连我都看得到防弹背心 你觉得他会看不到?
If I can see the vest, you don't think that he could see the vest?
就我一个去当诱饵 就我一个晾在明处
I'm the one that's baitin' him. I'm the only one not hidin' out.
穿了也没用
Ain't no thing.
要是Omar对你动手  准是朝着脑袋来一枪
'Cause when Omar come at you, he gon' be gunnin' at your head.
换我 我就会
I know I would be.
在Monk家门外等了一夜 天亮前他们走了
Stayed outside of Monk's all night. They left before morning though.
他们会回来的 肯定
They'll be back. No doubt.
有人担心这些谋杀案么?
Do you hear a lot of concern regarding these murders?
- 从没听人提起过啊 - 没么?
- I haven't heard anybody mention it. - No?
咱们接待的大部分人不是无家可归
Most of the folks we serve aren't actually homeless.
穷苦劳动力
Most are working poor.
这么说我刚采访的都不是...
So most of the people I interviewed here weren't...
流浪汉? 不 有些是的吧
Homeless? No. Some, maybe.
- 那你干嘛不... - 我看你干得挺欢实
- Why didn't you... - You seemed to be doing OK.
- 不想扫了你的兴嘛 - 那你说我该往哪儿去找?
- I didn't want to ruin it for you. - Where would you suggest I go?
大街上吧
Streets maybe.
太阳报派来的那记者
The reporter the Sun paper sent over,
可比不上Bob Woodward啊 (揭露"水门事件"的记者)
not exactly Bob Woodward.
干得漂亮啊 Bubs
Hell of a job, Bubs.
不过明天里间缺人端盘子
But we need help tomorrow waiting tables in the back room.
你要不愿干 我以后也不会问你了
If you don't like it, then I won't ask again.
要用双手握住 看见没
Gotta hold it with both hands, you know?
指哪儿打哪儿 明白吗?
Tryin' to hit what you aimin' at, a'ight?
跟电影里拍的不一样
It's not like they do in the movies.
好了 两腿分开
A'ight, so come on, spread your legs.
开枪首先得干什么?
What's the first thing you gotta do?
拉一下子弹上膛 像这样
Jack a round in the chamber. Like this, watch.
动手吧
Go ahead.
好难啊
It's hard to do.
好吧
A'ight.
这么着...
So then...
试试这个
try this.
丫就是一工具 跟活动扳手一样 没那么复杂好嘛?
It's a tool, just like a monkey wrench, that's all it is, a'ight?
- 我不知道原来会那么响 - 你干嘛要学这个?
- I didn't know it was gon' be so loud. - Why you want to do this?
你是怎么想的 Duke?
What is you thinkin', Duke?
你以为拿着枪人家就不敢欺负你了?
You think if you start carryin' ain't nobody gonna try you?
不 总有人会冲你来的
Nah. Somebody's always gonna try you.
你带着枪别人就会逼你拔枪
An' if you carryin' they gonna make you come out with it.
你拔了枪 就要准备一干到底
An' once you come out with it, you gotta be ready to go all the way.
要是不打算用你压根别带着
You can't bring it out unless you willin' to use it.
决不能有疑虑
Can't be no doubt.
靠 枪不会开 架不会打 站街角都不行
Man, can't shoot, can't fight. Can't even stand on the damn corner.
你有其他技能嘛 脑子那么好用
You got other skills, man. You smart like that.
我说Bunk  报纸上的东西可不能全信呐
I don't know, Bunk. You can't believe everything you read.
你个搅屎棍
Well, my little shit-stirrer.
根据你提出的增加人力和工时的要求
As per your request for additional manpower and man hours,
上头同意了无限制加班
unlimited overtime has been approved
不过只能办流浪汉谋杀这一件案子
for the investigation into the killings of homeless men
就你和另外一名探员
for you and one other detective only.
那监视组呢?
What about surveillance teams?
要蹲点把守 看着那帮老烟鬼的啊
We need to be watching places, watching the smokehounds.
就两名探员
Two detectives only.
就你和Greggs探员两人允许加班
You and stalwart detective Greggs here are what has been authorized.
- 其他的别想了 - 搞毛啊 Jay?
- Nothing beyond that. - What the fuck, Jay?
我这儿查的可是连环杀手啊
I'm working a serial killer here.
- 所以让你加班了嘛 - 可才两名探员怎么够
- Hence the overtime. - But two detectives working a red ball?
这城市到底怎么了?
What the fuck's wrong with this city?
至少得一打人才行
We need hours for a dozen men.
还需要监视车 摄像机
We need surveillance vehicles, cameras.
你想让我干什么?
What do you want from me?
你不是在查两周前那起三人命案么?
Ain't you still working that triple from two weeks ago?
我是有事儿要做  可Jay让我跟进你的案子
I got stuff I could run down on that, but Jay put me on this here.
过来
Come here.
你不觉得你太胡来了吗 不觉得吗?
Do you even see how fucking wrong you are? Do you even see it?
他们终于肯为这案子买单了 Bunk
They're gonna pay for this case Bunk.
- 这才是开始 - 什么案子?
- This is just the beginning. -Pay for What case?
你把人家真正在办案的探员拖过来
You just took a real detective off a real case behind your bullshit.
这我会想办法 不过这帮狗娘养的
I'll fix that. But eventually these motherfuckers
最终会为Marlo Stanfield的案子买单的 走着瞧吧
are gonna pay for us to do Marlo Stanfield. Just watch and learn.
我看你疯了吧 Jimmy 你看看你
You've lost your fucking mind, Jimmy. Look at you.
三天一大醉 每天一小醉
Half-lit every third night, dead drunk every second.
到处找妞睡 好不容易不醉不乱搞吧
Nut deep in random pussy. What little time you are sober and limp-dicked,
你居然胡编乱造个案子出来办
you're working murders that don't exist.
加班费你拿着 办你的三人命案去吧
Take the O.T. And work your triple.
不用担心报告 我替你扛着
Don't worry about your reports, I'll cover you ???.
- 这算唱的哪出? - 办你的三人案吧
- What the fuck is going on? - Work your triple.
我的案件报告里到哪儿都把你写进去
I'll cover every hour of it from my case file.
打扰 先生
Excuse me, sir.
先生
Sir.
我是巴尔的摩太阳报记者 能跟你谈一下吗
I'm with the Baltimore Sun. Can I talk with you a minute?
你预约过了?
You make an appointment?
抱歉 我整个下午都约满了
Sorry. I'm booked up all afternoon.
我在采访近来流浪汉被杀事件
I'm doing a story on the homeless men who've been killed.
你听说过吗?
You heard about that?
你身上有没有两块钱?
You got two dollars on you, right?
请问最近发生的谋杀有没有对
I was wondering if the murders had changed things
你和这里其他人的生活造成影响
for you and the other fellas out here.
你想知道谁是杀人犯吗
You wanna know about them murders?
- 我就是来问这个的 - 想知道是谁干的吗?
- That's why I'm here. - Wanna know who's doing it?
- 你知道是谁干的? - 正是
- Do you know who's doing it? - I do.
- 你能接受得了真相吗? - 你叫什么名字?
- Can you handle hearing it? - What's your name?
Nathan Levi Boston
Nathan Levi Boston.
你知道是谁杀的人?
And you know who the killer is?
你相信撒旦会化身成人行走在世间吗?
Do you believe Satan walks the earth in a fleshly form?
相信他会占据人的灵魂吗?
That Satan can occupy the souls of men?
他这才刚刚开始
And he's just getting started.
末日来临前还将会有更多杀戮
There's gonna be a lot more dead before it's over.
几百人 甚至几千人
Hundreds. Maybe thousands.
他们还让你在这破地方工作啊 难以置信
They still got you working outta this shithole? I don't believe it.
不算啥 倒是好几个月没大老板找得到我了
It ain't much but it's been months since a boss has been able to find me.
你对Marlo Stanfield还有兴趣吧?
You still have some interest in Marlo Stanfield, right?
这是他手机号
That's his cell.
他早就不用手机了
He stopped using cellphones.
Ellis 怎么来的?
Ellis, how?
警方工作呗 探员 警察的工作啊
Police work, detective.Police work.
你们还送外卖吗 给我来份胡椒牛排
Y'all still open for carryout? I want some of that pepper steak.
打错了 白痴
Wrong number, fool.
我也想说这事让我很震惊
I wish I could tell you it's a shock
但市里这事儿天天有
but it seems to happen in every city
但凡想在权力机构里立足
where we get us a place inside the power structure
- 总会成为众矢之的 - 这话说得没错
- and we become targets. - I know you're right.
这不是黑白种族的问题  州法官Bond先生 他也是黑人
It's not saying is a black-white thing. The State's Attorney, Mr. Bond, he's black.
但只要能让他往上爬
But if it serves his purpose -
让他的名字出现在新闻里 提升形象
gets his name in the news, ups his profile
幕后操控的人说什么他就会干什么
he'll do whatever the folks pulling the strings want.
管他是指鹿为马
Whether it be character assassination,
还是借刀杀人 等等
tie the noose in the rope, whatever.
但这次他挑错对象了
But they picked the wrong man this time.
- 他们还没听到你的回应吧 参议员 - 我不是找他们打架去的
- They must not heard about you, Senator. - I don't run from a fight.
- 我知道 - 人民知道
- I know that. - The people know.
我说的是广大人民群众...
I'm talkin' 'bout the people now...
他们知道我为西区和本市办了多少实事
The people know what I've done for West Baltimore and this city ???.
他们知道我每天面临的斗争
They know the battles I fight every day.
他们知道这些指控不过是些狗屁
They know these charges ain't nothing but B.S.
悠着点 这可是电台
Hey. Hold it now, it's radio.
注意文明用语 知道了
I gotta hold my tongue, I know.
我可不想你们被吊销广播执照
I don't want nobody pullin' y'all's license,
免得我话都没处说
so I can't say it like I feel it.
但我很高兴今晚来到你们的节目
But I wanted to come here on your show tonight
感谢你给我这次机会 好兄弟
and thank you so much for the opportunity, my brother
我想让你的听众从我嘴里首先听到
but I wanted your listeners to be the first to hear it from my mouth.
我是清白的
I have committed no crime,
我将不畏艰难险阻为人民服务
and I am gonna keep on doing the people's work without breaking stride.
非常感谢 参议员
I want to thank you for that, Senator.
另外大家注意明天两点在
And also I want everybody to know there's going to be a gathering
Mitchell法院将有一次集会
at the Mitchell courthouse tomorrow at 2:00
欢迎市民踊跃表达看法
so that people can be heard on this.
- 希望大家会积极前往 - 两点 Calvert大街
- I hope they come out in good numbers. - 2:00 on Calvert Street.
- 是时间让大家畅所欲言了 - 说的是
- It's time to lift every voice. - I heard that.
三名探员24小时监听
Three detectives for a 24-hour wiretap.
外加四人编成两组跟踪监视
Four more in two-man surveillance teams.
两辆不带警牌的车
A pair of unmarked cars.
我又不是狮子大开口 Cedric
I'm not asking the world here, Cedric.
Lester 我要有早给你了
Lester, if I had it, you'd have it.
这是手里捏着22条人命的混账的手机号
That's the cell number of the motherfucker who put 22 bodies on us.
- 去找他妈市长嘛! - 我去找过了
- Go to the fucking mayor! - I've been to the mayor.
我跪着去求了他两次  一次还是你的案子 你忘了?
I've been to him on my knees twice. Once for your case, remember?
好不容易批了两个人查Clay Davis
And all I could bring back was two men to work Clay Davis.
昨天凶杀组在办的那件流浪汉谋杀 也只给了两个人
And yesterday, for the serial killer that homicide was working, two men only.
我已经尽心尽责 每次都找到上面去
I've done my job. I've gone up the ladder every time.
可这连环杀手都只能批两名探员
But if a fucking serial killer can't bring back more than a couple detectives,
你新弄到个电话号码算什么玩意儿啊
what the hell does it matter that you have a fresh phone number?
公共信息部说上面派了更多人手
More manpower's been assigned, according to the P. I.O.
还有呢?
And?
查到第一个被害人是前海军陆战队员 越战时拿过铜奖章
I led with the first victim. Ex-marine. Bronze-star in Vietnam.
他家人求他回去 他有时也肯
His family begged him to come home, which he would do now and then,
但被杀前他们已经有一个月没见他了
but they hadn't seen him in a month before the murder.
好东西 非常好
Good shit. Real good shit.
迟到了 不过你有好消息吧?
Late, but you got the goods, right?
这些家伙一半都吸毒 不吸毒的也只想问我要钱...
Half of these guys are whack jobs, the other half just want to borrow a fin...
不过我找到好东西了
But yeah, I got good stuff.
Hanover街大桥下的一家四口
Got a family of four under the Hanover Street Bridge.
当爹的被我问得失声痛哭
Father broke down and cried when I talked to him,
说他怎么怎么不能自保 不能保护孩子
talking about how he couldn't protect himself, couldn't protect his kids.
当妈的只管抚摸着小儿子的金色头发
Mother just kept stroking the youngest one's blonde hair.
- 这回有名字吧? - 有
- We got names on this, right? - Yeah.
那男的叫...
Guy's name is...
Boston  Nathan Levi Boston
Boston. Nathan Levi Boston.
好 你要写就给你30英寸版面
OK, you got 30 inches, if you need them.
你接着Alma和Fletch的头版写个续篇
You're going off the front in a package with Alma and Fletch.
Olesker写了篇很不错的专栏  本地新闻版
Olesker wrote a pretty damn good column, too, for metro front.
去去 快写去
Go, go. Write, write.
这桩连环杀人案让某个巴尔的摩人 非常非常高兴啊
This serial killer is making one Baltimorean very, very happy.
Clay Davis
Clay Davis.
有了新的热点 他的起诉就能撤下头版了
One news cycle, and his indictment's gonna be off the front page.
越血腥越好卖嘛
Well, if it bleeds, it leads.
扯他妈的连环杀手
A fucking serial killer.
我编了个疯狂性变态  够他们大动干戈的
I give them a sex-crazed madman who's enough of a freak show
原以为会闹得全城沸沸扬扬 结果呢?
to get the whole city hot and bothered and what comes back?
就他妈派了一个人
One fucking detective.
派了谁? Kima Greggs 还嫌三人命案不够她忙的
And who is it? Kima Greggs, who should be working her triple.
我总不能拉她来 耽搁了正经案子吧
So now I can't give you her hours without fucking up honest casework.
现在简单了 Jimmy 我们不需要太多
Well, now it's easier, Jimmy. We don't need as much.
只要台监听设备
Now we need a wiretap.
这个可以我来干
I can monitor that myself.
反正就算查到啥也是违法的
Shit, anything we get up is gonna be illegal anyway.
还是不要让人知道得好
So we don't want anyone getting near it.
最多找Sydnor 我相信他
Sydnor, maybe. I can trust him.
要是从电话上查出什么
You start pulling information off that phone,
那至少要两辆监视车跟踪巡逻
you're gonna need at least a couple of surveillance cars in the street.
等查到再说吧
We'll worry when we get there.
关键是他这样事情倒好办了
The important thing is that he's making it easy for us.
以前正面交锋 那得要多少东西?
Before, with all that face-to-face, we were gonna need what?
远程摄像头 麦克风
Remote cameras, microphones,
六名探员24小时追踪监视
half-a-dozen guys working surveillance 24 hours.
现在他肯用手机 就逃不出我掌心
But now he's talking on a phone, and I got him.
要怎么从连环谋杀案上挤出台监听设备来?
So how do we squeeze a wiretap out of my serial killer?
他得给人打电话
He's gotta call someone.
打给谁?
Who?
主教Keeler
Cardinal Keeler.
Cal Ripken 管他谁 (美国职棒大联盟球员)
Cal fucking Ripken. Who gives a fuck?
法院的报告上随便编个号码
A bullshit number on the paperwork to the courthouse,
实际监听的是Marlo的手机号
Marlo's cell number on the tap itself.
太他妈天才了...
This is fucking genius...
才怪
Or not.
要是案子的事情 你得接电话啊
If that's about your case, you need to answer it.
别忘了你在破连环杀手案呢
Remember you're working a serial killer.
不 是我前妻 给我打了一晚上电话了
Nah, it's my ex-wife. Been calling all night.
好像我闲的没事儿似的
Like I got time for her fucking bullshit.
要让他们相信是你那凶手打的电话 才肯出钱让你搞监听
They got to believe it's your killer calling before they'll pay for a wiretap.
好吧 豁出去了
Well, fine. Fuck it.
给你伙计Oscar打电话 说还要具尸体
Call your buddy Oscar, tell him we need another body.
等着这死变态给Ripken先生打电话
The sick motherfucker is gonna call Mr. Ripken
说点只有凶手才知道的细节
with something only the killer could know.
看不把他们吓得拿出些监听设备来
That should shake 'em up enough for a couple of wiretaps.
Monk提早退休还挺乐呵的
Monk sure do like to retire early.
进去仨出来一个
Three go in and one come out.
胜算大了些
Better odds.
再等下去 把握会更大
We're gonna wait on it though. They'll get better still.
今晚不行 还有明晚
If not tonight, then the next.
你挺有耐心啊
You're a patient man.
他也是
Him too.
我打了你一天手机了
I tried to reach you on your cell all day.
- 我打给Beadie 她也不知道... - 我知道 是我的错
- I called Beadie, she had no idea... - I know. It's my fault.
- 他们还醒着? - 嗯
- They still up? - Yes.
嗨 伙计们
Hey, guys.
嗨 爸爸
Hey, dad.
听着Sean 我千方百计想赶去你的演出
Listen, Sean, I did everything I could to get to your play tonight.
嗨 Mike
Hey, Mike.
没什么 别内疚了
- It's cool. - No worries.
你妈说你表演得可棒了
Your mom said you were great.
要不你就这么弹弹呗 让我听听
Why don't you do it now? Let me hear it.
不行 这样听起来特烂 得看全场演出才有效果
I don't know. It's lame like that. You gotta see the whole play.
- 这什么乐队啊? - 死亡草原
- What band is that? - Dead Meadow.
- 死亡金属(metal)? - 草原 死亡草原
- Dead metal? - Meadow. Dead Meadow.
Ramones有什么问题么? (美国70年代金属乐队)
What the hell's wrong with the Ramones?
我下星期将功补过 带他们看球赛去
I'll make it up next weekend. Take 'em to the ball game.
这可是过日子 Jimmy
Hey, this is life, Jimmy.
这些才是真正重要的事情
This is the stuff that actually matters.
- 我知道 - 我跟Beadie谈过了
- I know. - I talked to Beadie.
她知道你心不在了 就像我当初
She knows she's losing you. Like I knew.
不是我说三道四
I'm not judging.
这么说也不是故意伤你心
I'm not saying this to hurt you.
但她都知道的
But she knows.
她都准备着要失去你了 像我当初一样
And she's ready for it, the way that I was ready for it.
你酗酒 整夜不归
You're drinking. You're out all night.
你去哪儿她根本不知道
She doesn't know where you are.
她又不是傻瓜 Jimmy
And she's no fool, Jimmy.
我很难过陪着你的不是我...
I'm sad that it wasn't with me...
但我好歹为你高兴
but I'm glad for you.
真的 你能相信吗?
I know, you can imagine that?
我很高兴你能找到她
I was glad that you found her.
我甚至也为她高兴
I was glad for her, even.
有一阵子 我从没见你那么开心过
For a while there, you were happier than I've ever seen you.
她人很好
She's great.
真的
She is.
别这样
Don't do this.
嘿
hey
你好哇 Bubs?
You all right, Bubs?
很好 很好
I'm good. good
就是有件事一直在脑子里
Except for somethin' that's been on my mind.
- 要是你忙的话... - 你说 没事儿的
- But I see you into somethin'... - I can take a minute.
有件事我一直想知道 但不确定有没有勇气接受
Need to find somethin' out. But I don't know if I really wanna know.
能知道最好 Bubs 我就是活证据
It's best to know, Bubs.  I'm living proof.
现在他们有能控制的药了
They got drugs an' shit now.
你怎么现在想起这事儿来?
Why's it on your mind now?
我听你的 在生命之家当志愿者
Been volunteering down Viva House, doin' like you told me.
可他们想让我端盘子
Man say he want me to serve food.
那没事儿 不通过这个传播的
You can. It don't travel like that.
话是这么说 可我总...
I know they say so, but I feel...
我不知道
I don't know.
我昨天去医院 都走到了大门口 可...
I went down to the clinic yesterday, got as far as the door, but...
一个人挺难吧
Tough to go alone.
是
Yeah.
等我十分钟
Give me 10 minutes.
今天该写些什么呢?
So, where do we take it today?
除非案情有进展 我们能写的都写了
Unless the story develops, I think we've covered the bases.
Alma可以跟进一下
Alma can check on things
看看到下午之前有什么新消息
and see where we're at by afternoon.
你还欠我篇Govans的报道呢
You owe me a Govans story.
再联系下Shane看看学校有什么进展
And you need to get with Shane on with that school series.
那啥 Gus 我觉得这事儿还没完
I don't know, Gus. I think this thing has legs.
也许我可以跟警察出勤 看他们警告流浪人员
Maybe I go out with the cops. Watch 'em warn the homeless.
想法不错 但这事儿交给Alma办去好了
Good thought, but Alma can work that into whatever she has.
进来
Yeah?
嘿
hey
忙吗?
Busy?
不忙...
No, just...
Jimmy还没来呢
Jimmy's not in yet.
我知道 还没睡醒呢
I know. He's sleeping one off.
- 值夜班吧? - 他们现在都这样
- Late night, huh? - They're all like that now.
放心 我不是刺探消息来的
Relax, I'm not looking for a snitch.
我知道你跟他是破案搭档 我不在乎
I know you're his partner in crime. I don't care.
Beadie
Whoa, Beadie.
我只想知道他究竟是想怎么样
I just want to know from you where this is going.
你跟他熟 知道他什么能做什么不能做
I mean, you know him. You know what he can and can't do.
这我可说不上
Don't know if I can speak on that.
我已经准备跟他断了 知道吗?
Look, I'm ready to put him out, OK?
为了我 为了我的孩子们...
For me, for my kids...
要是到最后 发现他就是这样的人
I mean, if in the end, if this is all there is to him.
要是他没法变好怎么办 我得先知道
If he can't be better than this, I just want to know.
他这不是忙着办案嘛
He's working this case right now.
连环杀手呢
Serial killer, actually.
别跟我说是案子害的 骗骗老百姓还成
Don't tell me this is about a case. Try that shit on some civilian.
遇上这么大压力 喝一杯要是难免的嘛
Look, he'll get his head in a certain place, he'll take a drink.
很多人都会这样
I mean, a lot of us will.
已经不是喝酒的问题了
It's more than a drink he's taking.
Beadie 你的事我没法指手画脚
Beadie, I can't tell you what to do.
我也不想放弃
I don't like giving up.
我得回去工作去了 谢谢你听我吐槽
OK, I gotta go back to work. Thanks for letting me vent.
你想今天开始吗?
You want to get started today?
- 最好赶快决定... - 吃过午饭再说吧
- Sooner we decide on... - After lunch, yeah.
- 总算找到血管了 - 嗯
- Finally found a line, huh? - huh.
不容易啊 都躲了好几年了
Know that wasn't easy. They been hidin' for years.
- 我可是专家 - 我也是
- I'm a pro. - Me, too.
我问你
Let me ask you...
结果什么时候能出来?
When do the results come back?
做完测试一个小时就行
About an hour from this test.
行了
There you go.
他们想蒙蔽我们
And they want you to believe that
全凭他们的一面之辞
there's only one side to this story,
妄称证据确凿不可推翻
and that their so-called facts cannot be denied.
但事实的真相在我们手中 对不对?
But we have some facts of our own, don't we?
对!
Yeah!
我们知道谁是我们的领袖
We know who our leaders are.
我们不要别人替我们选领袖 对不对?
And we don't want them  picking our leaders for us, do we?
对
No!
我们不能白白站着
And we will not stand idly by
让他们找我们领袖的碴
as they single out our leaders
来选择性地起诉
and selectively prosecute
或者说迫害他们
or should I say persecute them
就因为他们有勇气
just because they have the courage
坚韧不拔地为我们出头
and the fortitude to stand up for us.
让他们听到你的声音
Let them hear you.
听到你们的大声呼吁
Let them hear you loud and clear.
Clay Davis哪儿都不去 对不对?
Clay Davis isn't going anywhere, is he?
对!
No!
我们需要他 我们要保住他
We need him, we're going to keep him,
敢和我们唱反调的都去死
and damn anyone who says otherwise.
Clay Davis!
我怎么听说你不愿意背水一战了?
What the fuck is this I hear about you might not stand tall on this?
哪儿的话 我一定奋战到底
You got that wrong, old friend. I'm gonna carry this.
那还差不多 你要想退缩
You damn sure better. Because if you don't
从今往后直到你老死
you won't squeeze another greenback out of this town
在这城里可是一分钱都捞不到
for the rest of your natural life.
* We shall not be *
* we shall not be moved *
哎呦 看看呐
Lookie here.
- 这什么呀? - 换换口味
- The fuck is that? - Change of pace.
穿着衣服看上去也挺性感的
They look kinda hot with their clothes on.
喂 Clarice (《沉默的羔羊》女主角)
Hey, Clarice.
你那连环杀手给太阳报打电话了
Your serial killer called the Baltimore Sun.
有人声称是杀手本人 打给了个记者
Some goof claiming to be your guy called a reporter.
- 就是报道这事那人 - 恶作剧电话吧
- Someone's writing this shit up. - Must be a crank call.
有可能
Probably so.
不过事关混蛋报纸
But seeing as it's the fucking newspaper
你赶快过去 把这事搞定
you go over there and you set them straight.
你看吧
Go ahead.
阴性
Negative.
- 阴性说明... - 我知道
- Negative means... - I know what it means.
- 肯定搞错了 - 错不了
- Must be wrong. - It ain't wrong.
我干了那么多混账事儿
All the shit I've done.
一起抽了那么多东西 和我好兄弟
All the works I shared. My best boy years back?
我跟他用一个针管几十次了
I fired off the same hypo as him. ???
他可是绝对得病的
He had the bug for sure.
这玩意儿肯定不准
That shit ain't right nohow, man.
你失望了
You're disappointed.
这跟病毒压根没关系吧?
Shit, this ain't about the bug, is it?
你想让过去的一切产生意义寻找因果
This is you, tryin' to make the past  be everything, mean everything.
却想都不愿想此时此地发生的事情
You don't even wanna think about the here and now.
抱歉 Bubs
Sorry, Bubs.
耻辱没你想的那么值钱
Shame ain't worth as much as you think.
忘了吧
Let it go.
他说告诉大家他收手之前要杀满12人
He said he wanted people to know there'd be 12 bodies before he's finished.
他的原话 "我要带走12人"
He said, quote, "I came to take 12."
我说 "12人以后怎么办"
I said, "What happens after 12?"
他说 引号 我将前往他处 引号
He said, quote, "I go somewhere else," unquote.
我问起他咬痕 他说是他们让他咬的
I asked him about the bite marks. He said that they wanted him to bite.
他们自找的
And they ask for that.
他还抱怨说新闻把他写得像个变态
He complained that the article made him sound like a pervert.
我问他是不是怨恨他们
I asked him if he was angry at the men.
- 他就挂了 - 他打的你手机?
- He hung up. - He called you on your cellphone?
干嘛不给报社打?
Why didn't he call the paper?
我昨天到处跑给流浪汉发了不少名片
I was all over the city yesterday handing my cards out to homeless men.
他可能从名片上知道的
He probably got the number from a card.
操 可能我亲手给的他呢
Shit, I might've handed him a card.
我觉得就是他 害我头皮一阵发麻呢
I think this is the guy. I mean, a chill ran down my back.
这个说不准 万一是别的神经病
There's no way to know. I mean, if it's some other nut,
我们登出来不是像傻瓜一样
we're gonna look like fools if we print this.
你手机上有来电显示么 他打给你
Your cellphone caught the number? He dialed you.
有 我打回去了
Yeah, I dialed it back.
南Hanover街靠近西大街上的投币电话
Payphone on South Hanover near West Street.
- 他听起来什么样? - 什么意思
- What did he sound like? - What do you mean?
你们记者就靠和人讲话吃饭的
You talk to people for a living.
听起来是黑人 白人? 年轻人 老年人?
Did he sound black, white? Younger, older?
声音尖 声音粗?
High-pitched voice or low?
听起来 我觉得像是白人
He sounded, to me, like a white guy.
声音不算低 但很平静 没什么语调
Not a deep voice, but calm, almost monotone.
听起来挺老的 我看
He sounded older, I would say,
40左右吧 不算特别年轻
40s. Not a real young guy.
- 你笔记本能给我么? - 笔记不能给你
- Can I have your notebook? - You can't have his notes.
这不是保密来源  我们也不至于动用马里兰州盾牌法 (保护新闻记者法)
As this isn't a confidential source, we won't invoke the Maryland Shield law,
让他打印一份副本给你
but he'll type up a copy for you.
但笔记本本身归太阳报所有
But the actual document is property of the Baltimore Sun.
那还不去打 快啊
So type it up, like now.
你觉得这会是那杀手?
So, you're saying this could be the killer?
咱私底下说吧?
Can we talk off-the-record?
凶杀组今早接到一个电话
The homicide unit received a phone call this morning
从同一社区的投币电话打来的
from a payphone from the same neighborhood,
根据Scott对声音的描述 和提到的数字12
and based on Scott's voice description, and the use of the number 12,
总之必须找出是谁打的这俩电话
let's just say we need to find whoever made both those calls.
他打过别的电话?
He made another call?
探员 作为新闻工作人员
Detective, as a newsman,
如果杀手联系我们记者这一消息确凿
I'm inclinedto include these details  in our coverage
我有义务将这些内容写进报道
if there's a credible chance the killer was in contact with our reporter.
这会影响你们案件的侦破吗?
Would doing so affect  on your investigation?
说实话  这些电话是我们捉拿此人的重要渠道
Actually, these calls are our best means of finding this guy.
他打的每个电话 说的每句话 对你们我们
Every call he makes, every word he says, to you and to us,
都是重要的线索
can only provide information.
- 如果我们要报道此事... - 你们不能写他联系了警方
- If we do run a story... - You can't say he's contacting police.
无论如何都不能付诸报端
You can't print that under any circumstances.
那我们该如何
OK, then how do we characterize
警方对他给Scott打电话的回应?
what the police think about this call to Scott?
你可以说我们....
You can say we're...
会严肃对待
taking it seriously.
进一步说 你们是否可以单方同意
Going forward, is it possible that you would grant a one-party consent
让我们监听你们记者的手机和办公电话?
for us to monitor your reporter's  cellphone and office phones?
- 绝对不行 - 抱歉 探员
- Absolutely not. - I'm sorry, detective,
我们新闻行业的根本
but our ability to report is dependent upon
在于对谈话内容的保密性
our maintaining the confidentiality of our conversations.
提供信息我们完全愿意
We're perfectly willing to share the information
这个人他也不是什么保密信息源
this individual has as he's definitely not a confidential source.
但我们绝不同意巴尔的摩警察局
But we're not going to consent to the Baltimore Police Department
监听我们的电话
monitoring our phones.
- 你会监听投币电话? - 这个也别登
- You'll tap the payphone? - Don't print that either.
凶手打电话的地点也不要提起
Don't print anything about where the killer calls from.
他会换区域
He'll change up.
好吧 我马上去把笔记打出来
Well, I'll type up my notes quick.
对你们是件大新闻吧?
Big story for you guys, huh?
十分钟前我还说这事儿是狗屁呢
??? 10 minutes ago I'd've said this whole thing was bullshit.
世事难料啊 我看
Shows what I know, I guess.
...所以我将力战到底
...which is why I'm gonna fight this thing.
我是无辜的 我所做的一切都只为服务群众
I am innocent and I have done nothing except serve the people.
我相信你 参议员
Oh, I believe you, Senator.
你为社区做出的贡献有目共睹
I've seen the good work you've done for the community...
是Eddie Cantor的歌吧?
That's Eddie Cantor, right?
不是
No.
完美
It's perfect.
McNulty 太完美了
McNulty, it's perfect.
真不敢相信 我坐在那儿
I couldn't believe it. I'm sitting there,
听他们问各种狗屁 妈的 真是浪费时间
all this bullshit coming at me, thinking, Christ, this is a waste of time.
然后我突然想到这下有监听了 白白送上门的机会
Then I realized this is the wiretap. Right here. They're giving it to me.
别管我打了什么伪装电话了
Never mind me making a crank call.
Lester Freamon的监听设备这下有了
This here is Lester Freamon's motherfucking wire.
万一查起来怎么办?
What if they check this?
这组能有多少人装过监听仪?
How many guys in this unit have ever hooked up a wiretap?
他们不知道哪根接哪根的
They don't know which wire goes where.
再跟我讲讲
Explain it to me again,
我觉得自己够聪明了 可这还是闹得我头疼
because I think I'm a smart guy, but this shit makes my head hurt.
他们以为监听的是连环杀手的手机
They think they're up on your killer's cellphone,
但是什么都不会听到 因为这根没接上
but they'll never catch a call because this goes nowhere.
同时 借着同一项法庭授权
And meanwhile, using the same court authorization,
我在下面用真正的线路监听Marlo
I'm on the live wire down at the detail office, listening to Marlo.
每天 你的记录和法庭报告上
Every day, you file office and court reports
都写没有连环杀手的新消息
saying there's been no further contact with the serial killer.
而我报告上不写 但用听来的消息
I file exactly nothing, but use what I hear
去对付我们真正的敌人
to rig the case on our real target.
- 等案子上了法庭... - 监听一词绝口不提
- And when it goes to court... - No mention of a wiretap.
- 就说是线人提供的消息 - 就这样
- It's all based on a C. I. - There it is.
法官签署的四份授权令
Four copies signed by the judge.
对一部手机进行紧急拦截监听
Emergency order for telephonic intercept of a cellphone,
号码是410-915-0909
number 410-915-0909.
只要机器接好 你们就可以开始了
If the machine is rigged, you're good to go.
行了
You're up.
- 捕猎愉快 - Howie 你值半夜的班
- Good hunting - Howie, you got midnight shift.
Worden六点钟来换你
Worden'll be in to relieve you at 6.
Worden之后 我的小队负责白天监听
After Worden, my squad will pick up monitoring on the dayshift.
借过
Excuse me.
别苦着脸 我们付加班费的
Don't look so pissy. We're actually paying overtime for this.
O-dog!O-dog!
我的腿!
My leg!
他妈的趴下!
Stay the fuck down!
搞什么
What the...
妈的
Damn.
播出电话
搞什么...
What the...